Register of the Peruvian Subject Collection, 1949-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
Peruvian Subject Collection,
1949-1995
XX807
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, bulletins, and studies relating primarily to political conditions and elections in Peru, and to communist and guerrilla movements in Peru.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Peru--Politics and government.; Elections--Peru.; Communism--Peru.; Guerrillas--Peru.; Communism.; Peru.
Series Description
- Subject File, 1949-1994 (Box 1)
  Pamphlets, reports, serial issues, speeches and leaflets, principally concerning political and economic conditions. Includes material on revolutionary movements
Container List
*See card catalog for increments that may have been added since December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1949-1994
  - General. Pamphlets, 1969-1980. Includes analyses of the military, the Catholic church, liberation theology, youth issues and a speech by Juan Velasco Alvarado (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Economic conditions. Pamphlets, 1970-1977. Includes material published by the Ministry of the Economy and Finances (Folder 2)
  - Elections, 1990. Reports written by Michael Radu. In English (Folder 3)
  - Foreign relations. Pamphlets and text, 1949-1994. Includes material published by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and a speech by Fernando Belaunde Terry (Folder 4)
  - Political parties and revolutionary movements
    - General. Serial issue and leaflet, 1977-1982. Includes material relating to trade unions and Marxist-Leninist (Maoist) current independent of other parties (Folder 5)
    - Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria (MIR). Serial issue, published clandestinely, 1970 (Folder 6)
    - Partido Comunista del Peru ("Sendero Luminoso")
      - General. Pamphlet and leaflet, 1987-1992. Includes a speech by "Presidente Gonzalo" (Abimael Guzman) (Folder 7)
      - Foreign support groups. Serial issues and pamphlets, 1992-1993. Includes material published by the Revolutionary Communist Party (USA) relating to the imprisonment of Abimael Guzman (Folder 8)
    - Partido Comunista Peruano. Pamphlets, 1969. Includes documents relating to Fifth Party Congress (Folder 9)
    - Partido Socialista Revolucionario. Pamphlets, 1977. Includes analysis of governmental economic policy (Folder 10)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 2)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.